<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Get. Shit. Done.]]></title><description><![CDATA[Personal blog by David O'Regan. I explain with words and code.]]></description><link>http://doregan.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 15:54:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Ambition]]></title><link>http://doregan.com//ambition/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://doregan.com//ambition/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Being Ok With Deploying Shitty Code]]></title><description><![CDATA[So, at some point in your career as a software developer, you’re going to run into a moment of:  . Don’t panic, it’s a normal reaction and a…]]></description><link>http://doregan.com//being-ok-with-shitty-code/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://doregan.com//being-ok-with-shitty-code/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;So, at some point in your career as a software developer, you’re going to run into a moment of: &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Shit, deploy or keep tweaking?&lt;/code&gt;. Don’t panic, it’s a normal reaction and a cross roads we all come to eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think of yourself as a good developer, you probably spend a lot of time trying to improve the quality of your own code. Even if you dont think you’re a particulary good developer, I bet you still spend a lot of time trying to write the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You spend time reading best practices from your developer heros - Looking at you &lt;a href=&quot;http://jussi.hallila.com/&quot;&gt;Jussi Hallila&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You refactor your old awful code time and time again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You curl up in the corner and cry yourself stupid after trying to remove all the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; statements from your latest pet project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, we spend a lot of time and energy trying to perfect our own craft, writing code that other people will awe at but how does this type of idealism stack up in the real world against business requirements?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, theres a bit of a disconnect between what developers feel they need to deliver and what we actually need to deliver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why though?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we like to feel smart, sometimes we want to prove we know what we’re doing, sometimes we need to push ourseleves. None of these motivations however relate at all to buisness value delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we write code, the end goal should &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; be to deliver the most amount of value to the person at the other end of our program. Or in other words, your value as a developer shouldnt be measured in the quality of your code but rather the quality of the application you deliver to your user.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>